Guide to the R. O. (Reuben Oscar) Everett Papers, 1913-1971
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
R. O. (Reuben Oscar) Everett papers 1913-1971
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Everett, R. O. (Reuben Oscar), 1879-1971
4.0 Linear Feet 156 Items
Attorney in Durham, N.C. His wife and son were also prominent N.C. lawyers.
The R. O. Everett Papers span the years 1913-1971. Collection includes Everett’s extensive diaries, 1915-1971, chronicling Everett's professional career, his interests, his family's careers, and social, civic and historical aspects of life in Durham, N.C. The collection also contains a small amount of correspondence, clippings, lecture notes, printed material, pictures, and other papers. In addition, transcripts for all the diaries in the collection have been converted to electronic documents that have been transferred to the Special Collections file server.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The R. O. (Reuben Oscar) Everett Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1982.
Collection Overview
The R. O. Everett Papers span the years 1913-1971, centered around Everett’s extensive diaries, 1915-1971, chronicling in detail Everett's professional career beginning in Durham N.C., his interests, his family's careers, and social, civic and historical aspects of life in Durham, N.C. Of particular interest are his discussions of legal cases and local politics. The collection also contains a small amount of correspondence, clippings, lecture notes, printed material, pictures, and other papers. Transcripts for all the diaries in the collection have been converted to electronic documents that have been transferred to the librar file server. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these files before coming to use the collection.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Everett, R. O. (Reuben Oscar), 1879-1971
Lawyers -- North Carolina -- Durham
Durham (N.C.) -- History
Durham (N.C.) -- Politics and government
North Carolina -- Politics and government
Diaries
Machine-readable records
Photographs
Contents of Collection
- R. O. (Reuben Oscar) Everett Papers, 1913-1971, (11 boxes)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Clippings
  - Printed Materials
  - Miscellany
  - Pictures
  - Diary (typescripts), 1915-1919, 1920-1921, 1966-1969
  - Lecture Notes, 1913,1914, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1915-1921
  - Diary, 1923-1929 (Box 3)
  - Diary, 1930-1936 (Box 4)
  - Diary, 1937-1942 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1943-1948 (Box 6)
  - Diary, 1949-1954 (Box 7)
  - Diary, 1955-1958 (Box 8)
  - Diary, 1959-1962 (Box 9)
  - Diary, 1963-1968 (Box 10)
  - Diary, 1969-1971 (Box 11)